Josephine Schain Papers, 1907-1960
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Josephine Schain papers
1907 - 1960
Schain, Josephine, 1886-1972
MS 139
15 boxes (5.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Settlement house worker, suffragist, pacifist, and international relations specialist. Papers focus primarily on Schain's involvement in a host of women's organizations, the purpose of which was advocacy of international peace through cooperative enterprise among nations. Types of material include radio broadcasts scripts, speeches, photographs, articles, and other writings. Notable correspondents include Margaret Corbett Ashby, Mary Ritter Beard, Carrie Chapman Catt (extensive), Newton Diehl Baker, Helen Gahagan Douglas, India Edwards, Helen Hayes, Lorena Hickok, Stanley Hornbeck, Cordell Hull, Rosa Manus, Alva Reimer Myrdal, Maud Wood Park, Frances Perkins, and Virginia Rishel.
Josephine Schain was born in Browns Valley, Minnesota in 1886 to Irene Burdick Schain and Jacob Theodore Schain. She earned her LL.B. from the University of Minnesota in 1908 and was awarded an honorary LL.D. by Smith College in 1937. She began her career as a social worker in Minneapolis, and worked as a settlement house worker on New York's East Side from 1918 to 1924. Schain was also active in the suffrage and peace movements, both as an organizer of conferences and similar events, and as a much sought after speaker. She spoke during the women's suffrage campaign in New York City in 1915 and wrote Women and the Franchise in 1918. She served as director of the Department of International Relations for the National League of Women Voters from 1924 to 1928, and as the national director of the Girl Scouts of America from 1930 to 1935. Schain chaired the National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War from 1936 to 1941, the Peace and Disarmament Committee of the Women's International Organizations from 1933 to 1938, the executive committee of the Women's Centennial Congress in 1940 and the Pan-Pacific Women's Association from 1949 to 1955. Schain was also a member of the International Alliance of Women for Suffrage and Equal Citizenship from 1933 to 1938, the U.S. Delegation to the Conference on Food and Agriculture in 1943, and of the consultant group to the U.S. delegation to the United Nations Conference in San Francisco in 1945. To quote words spoken at Smith College when Schain was awarded an honorary degree there in 1937, she was "a devoted laborer and a valiant and effective leader in the cause of peace, freedom and justice among the peoples of the world." Josephine Schain died in 1972.
The Josephine Schain Papers, dating from 1907 to 1960, consist of 5 linear feet and are primarily related to Schain's involvement in a host of women's organizations, the purpose of which was advocacy of international peace through cooperative enterprise among nations. There is also a small amount of material relating to women and the vote, notably the Democratic National Committee, Empire State Campaign Committee, and the League of Women Voters. Types of material include correspondence, broadcasts, speeches and other writings; photographs; and journal and newspaper articles.
The bulk of the papers date from 1930 to 1955 and focus on Schain's work as an officer of numerous women's rights and peace organizations, as well as her role in organizing conferences and other events that they sponsored. Half the collection is comprised of material pertaining to those organizations, of which approximately two thirds is correspondence. The letters (in addition to minutes, agendas, bulletins, memoranda, and reports) provide excellent documentation of the internal workings of the organizations' leadership, and of perceptions of the issues the women involved were attempting to address and remedy, both nationally and internationally. Notable correspondents include Margaret Corbett Ashby, Mary Ritter Beard, Carrie Chapman Catt, Newton Diehl Baker, Helen Gahagan Douglas, India Edwards, Helen Hayes, Lorena Hickok, Stanley Hornbeck, Cordell Hull, Rosa Manus, Alva Reimer Myrdal, Maud Wood Park, Frances Perkins, and Virginia Rishel. The Carrie Chapman Catt correspondence is extensive, both with Schain and with others. The photographs in this collection are also noteworthy and include images of Catt and Schain, as well as group pictures taken at various international peace conferences.
This collection is organized into five series:
I. Biographical Materials
II. Correspondence
III. Writings
IV. Organizations
V. Subject Files
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
History of the Collection
Josephine Schain donated her papers to the Sophia Smith Collection from 1957 to 1964.
Search Terms
Ashby, Margaret Corbett - Correspondence; Beard, Mary Ritter, 1876-1958--Correspondence; Bompas, Katherine -- Correspondence; Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1859-1947; Edwards, India--Correspondence; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Correspondence; Hayes, Helen, 1900-- Correspondence; Hickok, Lorena A.--Correspondence; Hornbeck, Stanley Kuhl, 1883-1966 -- Correspondence; Manus, Rosa -- Correspondence; Rishel, Virginia, 1918- --Correspondence; Schain, Josephine, 1886-1972; League of Women Voters--History; National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War (U.S.); Pan Pacific and Southeast Asia Women's Association; Women's Centennial Conference; Democratic National Committee (U.S.)--History--Sources; International Alliance of Women--History--Sources; Inter-American Conference for the Maintenance of Peace (1936: Buenos Aires); Permanent Court of International Justice--History--Sources; International law--History--20th century--Sources; Peace--Congresses--History--Sources; Peace movements--History--Sources; Women and peace--History--Sources; Women--Congresses--History; Women--International cooperation--History--Sources; Women--Suffrage--United States--History--Sources
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS 1907-60, .5 linear ft.
  This series includes many newspaper clippings about Schain and her work; honors and awards, including certificates documenting her appointments to various delegations; invitations, notably to call on Presidents Hoover and Roosevelt, or their wives; and photographs of Schain, Carrie Chapman Catt, the Conference of the International Assembly of Women (1946), and the Pan-Pacific Women's Association Conference (1955).
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1915-54, .25 linear ft.
  This series is comprised primarily of letters between Schain and Carrie Chapman Catt; it also includes several third party letters to Catt, and a few letters and telegrams to Schain. There is further Catt correspondence in the Inter-American Conference for Peace subseries, located in SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS.
- SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES 1913-48, 1 linear ft.
  This series contains a copy of Schain's book Women and the Franchise, as well as typescripts and notes for her radio broadcasts and speeches on such topics as disarmament, military and diplomatic neutrality, how women's organizations might best pursue international work for the common good, and pacifism in general. This series also includes a scrapbook of editorial newspaper articles by Schain, and published versions of articles she wrote for various journals on the subjects of foreign affairs and international cooperation.
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS 1927-58, 2.25 linear ft.
  This series is the largest in the collection and in many ways is the heart of it. It consists mainly of correspondence between Schain and her colleagues the world over as they collaborated on national and international conferences, committees, and other projects relating to the pursuit of international peace initiated by women's organizations. The series also includes a smattering of agendas, minutes, bulletins, and reports for some of the organizations in which Schain was involved. The series is arranged alphabetically by name of organization, with correspondence and other types of material listed as subseries.
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES 1945-57, 1 linear ft.
  This series consists of photocopies of pages from a scrapbook compiled by Schain (mostly clippings about political issues), and of brochures, pamphlets and printed matter about countries in which Schain took an interest. Several issues of Middle East Forum are also included, as is a copy of the book The White Man's Dilemma: Climax in the Age of Imperialism by Nathaniel Peffer, which is inscribed by Carrie Chapman Catt.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS 1907-60
  - Correspondence and memoranda about Schain, 1910-14, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Magazine articles and clippings about Schain, 1907-54, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    [see also Oversize Materials]
  - Jupiter Rex Certificate, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    [see Oversize Materials]
  - Women of Achievement Award, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1907, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Poem about Schain, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Appointments to delegations, 1910-14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Trip to India: visa and visitor passes, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Invitations
    - White House, 1930-49, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - General, 1925-55, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous pass cards, business cards, and ephemera, 1924-49, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs
    - Josephine Schain, circa 1932-55, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Carrie Chapman Catt, 1936-40, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Groups, 1926-60 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Conference of the International Assembly of Women, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Pan-Pacific Women's Association Conference, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1915-54
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1915-41 (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
    [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS: Inter-American Conference for Peace]
  - Third party letters to Catt, 1926, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Woodward, Ellen, 1942-45 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General: A-Z, 1911-53 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified: "Helen," undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Telegrams, 1941-54, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES 1913-48
  - Scrapbook: clippings, Aug-Sep, 1913 (Box 3)
  - Book: Women and the Franchise, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Articles
    - General, 1913-47 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Democratic Digest, 1941-46, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Woman's Journal, Mar 1930 - May 1931 (photocopies of Schain's articles) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The Women's Press, Jun 1935 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Broadcasts
    - 1930-38 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - 1939-41, undated (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Speeches
    - General, 1909-48, undated (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - Democratic Party, 1940, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - International Alliance of Women, 1934-35 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - London Naval Conference, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War, 1937-40, undated (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
    - United Nations Conference on Peace and Agriculture, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brochures, pamphlets and posters, 1930-35, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Notebook of observations, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS 1927-58
  - American Association of University Women: correspondence and notes on 9th session of General Assembly, 1937-55 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Business and Professional Women's Club: correspondence, 1941-55, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Chautauqua Woman's Club
    - Correspondence and Chautauqua Summer School program, 1936, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets, 1940-43, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Country Women's Association of Australia: correspondence, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Democratic National Committee
    - Correspondence
      - Edwards, India, 1945-46 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Girton, Dorothy, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Hickok, Lorena, 1941-44 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - McAllister, Dorothy, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Rishel, Virginia, 1941-45 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Satterfield, Frances, 1944-45 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Stewart, Gertrude, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Tillet, Gladys, 1940-46 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Conference programs, 1941-45 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1943-46 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Democratic State Committee of New York: correspondence, 1936-44 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Girl Scouts of America: clippings, 1930-34 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Inter-American Conference for Peace
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1936-37 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Catt, Carrie Chapman
        [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE]
        - de Justo, Alicia Moreau, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 19)
        - Hayes, Helen, 1937-38 (Box 6, Folder 20)
        - New York Times, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 21)
        - Schain, Josephine, 1936, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
        - Others, 1936-37 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Memoranda, program, and proposed agendas, 1936, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, 1936-38, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - International Alliance of Women
    - Correspondence
      - Ashby, Margery Corbett, 1932-40 (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
      - Baker, Newton D., 1935 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Bakker-von Bosse, Christine, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Bompas, Katherine, 1932-39 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Gourd, Emilie, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Manus, Rosa, 1932-40 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Conferences: programs, reports, and clippings
      - Berlin, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Belgrade, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Istanbul, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Ceylon, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Constitution and committee reports, 1936-38, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - International Assembly of Women (South Kortright, NY)
    - Program, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Reports, notes, and lists of delegates, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Pamphlet: The World We Live In, The World We Want, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - International Children's Emergency Fund: correspondence, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - International Federation of Business and Professional Women: correspondence with Mary Ritter Beard, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - International Peace Campaign Conference (Brussels)
    - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Agendas, memoranda, and printed matter, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - League of Women Voters
    - Correspondence
      - Johnstone, Anne Hartwell, 1935-36 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Morgan, Ruth, 1924-33 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Morrison, Mrs. James, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Park, Maud Wood, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Clippings and programs, 1924-27, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Liaison Committee of Women's International Organizations: agendas, minutes, and pamphlets, 1936-55 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - London Naval Conference (regarding ratification of the London Naval Treaty), 1930
    - Clippings (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Notes (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Pamphlets (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Petitions (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Pro-ratification notes by Schain, and speech by Sen. David A. Reed (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - U.S. Senate Roll Call, 7 Jul 1930 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Women's Peace Crusade: press release, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War
    - Correspondence
      - Austin, Mrs. H. W. and Bronson, Mrs. H.S., 1935 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Frackt, Elizabeth, 1934, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Hornbeck, Stanley, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Perkins, Frances, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Roelofs, Henrietta, 1931-34 (Box 8, Folder 5)
        [see also YWCA]
      - Simonds, Frank H., 1935 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Woodsmall, Ruth, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Articles, bulletins, minutes, and reports, 1927-41, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Conferences
      - Third - Fifteenth Conferences on the Cause and Cure of War, 1928-40 (Box 8, Folder 9-13)
      - Popular Conference for the Peace of America (Buenos Aires): Schain's NCCCW credential and pass card, Nov 1936 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1929-41, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - National Council for the Prevention of War: correspondence, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - National Council of Women: correspondence, 1952-54 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Pan-Pacific Women's Association
    - Histories of the organization: typescripts, 1950-51, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Constitution, by-laws, and membership information, 1937-54, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - United States Mainland Committee: minutes, 30 Nov 1937 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Bulletins, Jul 1952 (#2)-Mar 1958 (#18)(incomplete run) (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Clippings, 1949-52 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Conferences
      - 1928, 1930 and 1934 (Honolulu, Hawaii): records of proceedings, 1928-34 (Box 8, Folder 23-25)
      - 1937 (Vancouver, British Columbia)
        - Correspondence
          - Parsons, Alice, 1937, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 1)
          - Satterthwaite, Anna, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 2)
          - Sweet, Georgina, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Programs, reports, and notes, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Record of proceedings, 1937-49 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - 1940 (New Zealand)
        - Correspondence
          - Andrews, Elsie, 1937-39 (Box 9, Folder 6)
          - Appleton, Viva B., 1939 (Box 9, Folder 7)
          - Bollert, Mary L., 1937-39 (Box 9, Folder 8)
          - Henry, Alice, 1937-38 (Box 9, Folder 9)
          - McLennon, Ethel, 1938-39 (Box 9, Folder 10)
          - Penington, Frances E., 1938 (Box 9, Folder 11)
          - Sullivan, Lily, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Memoranda, study guide, proposed agendas, and programs, 1939-40 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - 1949 (Honolulu, Hawaii)
        - Correspondence
          - Andrews, Harriet, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 14)
          - MacArthur, Douglas, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 15)
          - Mahon, Mrs. Burnett, 1949, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Memoranda, program, reports and notes, 1949, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - Records of proceedings, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - 1952 (Christchurch, New Zealand)
        - Correspondence
          - Barker, V. Duckworth, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 19)
          - Ford Foundation, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 20)
          - Kane, Amy, 1952-53 (Box 9, Folder 21)
          - Lea, Ellen B., 1952-53 (Box 9, Folder 22)
          - McLennon, Jessie, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 23)
          - Moore, Kathleen, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 24)
          - Robertson, Agnes, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 25)
        - Press release, programs, minutes, notes, and agendas, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 26)
        - Record of proceedings, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - 1955 (Manila, Philippines)
        - Correspondence
          - Andrews, Harriet, 1952-54 (Box 9, Folder 28)
          - Goh, Constance, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 29)
          - Handy, Willowdeen, 1952-55 (Box 9, Folder 30-31)
          - Kuppusamy, Mrs. V. D., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 32)
          - Khoo, Mrs. Shulen F., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 33)
          - Lea, Ellen, 1953-54 (Box 9, Folder 34)
          - Loh, S.C., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 35)
          - Mahon, Elsie, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 36)
          - Starbuck, Kathryn, 1954, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
          - Miscellaneous, 1952-55 (Box 9, Folder 38)
        - Programs, reports, notes, and agendas, 1954-55 (Box 9, Folder 39)
        - Record of proceedings, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - 1958 (Tokyo, Japan): record of proceedings, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1935-53 (Box 9)
  - Peace and Disarmament Committee of the Women's International Organizations
    - Correspondence
      - Arnold, Dorothy M., 1940 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - d'Arcis, Clara Guthrie, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Dingman, Mary A., 1936-39 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Heneker, Dorothy, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - YWCA: Henrietta Roelofs, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Annual report and memoranda, 1936-39 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Pamphlets, 1932-36 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Invitations received at Geneva conference, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Service Bureau for Women's Organizations: correspondence, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - South Pacific Commission: reports, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Summit County (Ohio) Federation of Democratic Women: correspondence, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - United Nations
    - General
      - Articles and posters, 1945-54, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Clippings, 1947-54, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Conference on Food and Agriculture
      - Correspondence: U.S. Department of State
        - Doran, Helen, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 14)
        - Hull, Cordell, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 15)
        - Stinebower, Leroy, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Invitations, programs, and Schain's pass card, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Notes and typescripts, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Clippings and pamphlets, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - U. N. Commission on the Status of Women: correspondence, newsletters, and reports, 1952-55 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - U.N. International Children's Emergency Fund (UNICEF): Committee membership lists and reports, 1953-55 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Votes for Women: Empire State Campaign Committee: correspondence, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE: Catt, Carrie Chapman]
  - Women's Centennial Congress
    - Correspondence
      - Mail and Express Printing Co., 1940-41 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Pelthick-Lawrence, Emmeline to Carrie Chapman Catt, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Sporburg, Constance A., 1941 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Pamphlets, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 26-27)
    - Clippings and reports, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom
    - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Memoranda, 1936, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Women's Joint Congressional Committee: correspondence and printed matter, 1930-37 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Women's Northeastern Democratic Association (Pennsylvania): correspondence, 1942-43 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Women's Peace Crusade: correspondence
    - Clark, Hilda, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Courtney, Kathleen, 1929-40, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - World Court
    - Correspondence, clippings, minutes, press releases, and reports, 1925-39, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Lobbyist's reports, 1923-24 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Pamphlet: The United States and the World Court by Philip C. Jessup, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Young Women's Christian Association: correspondence, 1935-39 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous women's clubs: pamphlets and programs, 1909-27 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous conferences and events: pamphlets, brochures, and notes, 1912-53 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES 1945-57
  - Book: The White Man's Dilemma: Climax of the Age of Imperialism by Nathaniel Peffer, 1927 [Located in Box 3] (Box 3)
  - Countries: brochures, pamphlets, and printed matter, 1941-57, undated
    - Australia, Ceylon, China, Fiji Islands, Germany, Hong Kong (Box 11, Folder 11-16)
    - India, Indonesia, Israel, Japan, Korea, Lebanon, New Guinea, New Zealand, and Pacific Islands (Box 12, Folder 1-11)
    - Pakistan, Philippines, Siam (Thailand), and Turkey (Box 13, Folder 1-7)
  - Journals: Middle East Forum, 1957-58 (Box 13, Folder 8-10)
  - Scrapbook: photocopies of pages of clippings and other ephemera, 1909-12 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Suffrage
    - Pamphlets
      - The Forward March: An Account of the Women's Movement in the Unite States by Olive A. Colton, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Then and Now by Carrie Chapman Catt, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Printed matter, 1912-15, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1914-16, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)